

elieyounan2@gmail.com

224-730-8665

https://gitlab.com/ elieyounan2

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Tire Center Supervisor with almost 10 years in the industry. High interest in technology and IT. I have enrolled in relevant foundational college course work in Computer Science and like to spend my free time on improving relevant skills that aren't offered via schools. I am an open minded, motivated individual who is willing to put in the work to learn from superiors.

## **EDUCATION**

Computer Science University of Iowa, Iowa City, Iowa 2018-Active enrollment.

Associate in Science Oakton Community College, Skokie, Illinois 2015-2018

#### **SKILLS**

- Java and Python (Java Data structure and Software development relevant college courses)
- Exposure and usage of Version Control Systems(Gitlab/Github)
- Exposure to HTML5/ CSS/Bootstrap by Udemy
- Languages:

   French(Read/Write),
   (Read/Write),
   Assyrian

• Basic Troubleshooting

# **RELEVANT COURSE WORK - PROJECTS**

- College Courses : Java Data Structure, Python.
- ServiceNow Platform (IT) Micro course.
- Independent courses with third party sites including Udemy: HTML5, CSS/Bootstrap.
- Implemented classes in Java using different structures from ArrayLists, Maps, Dictionaries to Iterators in order to solve a list of Queries that contained records of flights and manipulate such results.
- Fully developed a Java GUI application that can give accurate price quotes including certain conditions and parameters that is now actively being used by our tire shop.
- Successfully coded "TinDog", a website that helped me learn more about layout/design using Bootstrap/CSS.
- JPMorgan Virtual Experience Program Participant (2022) (6 hours). Participated in open access JPMorgan Virtual Experience Program with InsideSherpa completing the following short tasks: 1) Interface with a stock price data feed 2) Use JPMorgan Chase Frameworks and tools 3) Display data visually for traders.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Tire Shop Installer/ Supervisor (part-time) Costco Wholesale | Coralville,IA September 2018 - Current

- Kept team ready for daily demands with effective level of tools, equipment and replacement parts. Promoted performance-oriented culture with regular assessments of employee work.
- Minimized workplace hazards and accidents through continuous monitoring and training initiatives. Achieved work objectives by prioritizing jobs, organizing schedules and coordinatingassignments.
- Inspected and monitored work areas, examined tools and equipment, and provided employee safety training to prevent, detect, and correct unsafe conditions or violations of procedures and safety rules.
- Responded promptly to customer, vendor, and staff questions and quickly resolved issues, cultivating strong, long-term relationships.
- Collaborated positively with peers and other staff members to maintain friendly, supportive, and cooperative work atmosphere.
- Listened to customer requests and specifications and made suggestions to appropriately fulfill needs.
- Complied with corporate regulations, policies, and procedures to maximize safety, security, and overall trust in organization and employees.

Tire Technician
Sam's Club |
Evanston, Illinois

June 2015 - July 2018

- Mounted and balanced tires on personal and commercial vehicles.
- Supported customer decision-making, recommending appropriate repair treatment or replacement of tires.
- Completed maintenance in line with manufacturer specifications.
- Observed workplace safety requirements and performed repairs in alignment with company quality standards.
- Cleaned and tidied the shop, putting up new supplies and organizing tools to keep everyone focused on the customer's needs.